To tell the age of most layered rocks, scientists study the fossils these rocks contain.
要判断大多数层状岩石的年代，科学家会研究这些岩石中所含的化石。
Fossils provide important evidence to help determine what happened in Earth history and when it happened.
化石提供了重要证据，有助于确定地球历史上发生过什么以及发生在何时。
The word “fossil” makes many people think of dinosaurs.
“化石”这个词让许多人想到恐龙。
Dinosaurs are now featured in books, movies, and television programs, and the bones of some large dinosaurs are on display in many museums.
如今，恐龙出现在书籍、电影和电视节目中，一些大型恐龙的骨骼还在许多博物馆里展出。
These reptiles were dominant animals on Earth for well over 100 million years from the Late Triassic through the Late Cretaceous.
从三叠纪晚期到白垩纪晚期，在远超1亿年的时间里，这些爬行动物一直是地球上的优势动物。
Many dinosaurs were quite small, but by the middle of the Mesozoic Era, some species weighed as much as 80 tons.
许多恐龙体型相当小，但到了中生代中期，有些物种的体重达80吨之多。
By around 65 million years ago all dinosaurs were extinct.
到大约6500万年前，所有恐龙都已灭绝。
In spite of all of the interest in dinosaurs, they form only a small fraction of the millions of species that live and have lived on Earth.
尽管人们对恐龙兴趣浓厚，但在地球上现存和曾经存在过的数百万个物种中，恐龙只占很小一部分。
The great bulk of the fossil record is dominated by fossils of animals with shells and microscopic remains of plants and animals, and these remains are widespread in sedimentary rocks.
化石记录的绝大部分是有壳动物的化石和动植物的微体遗存，这些遗存广泛分布于沉积岩中。
It is these fossils that are studied by most paleontologists.
大多数古生物学家研究的正是这些化石。
In the late eighteenth and early nineteenth centuries, the English geologist and engineer William Smith and the French paleontologists Georges Cuvier and Alexandre Brongniart discovered that rocks of the same age may contain the same fossils even when the rocks are separated by long distances.
18世纪末和19世纪初，英国地质学家兼工程师威廉·史密斯以及法国古生物学家乔治·居维叶和亚历山大·布隆尼亚尔发现，即使相隔遥远，同一年代的岩石也可能含有相同的化石。
They published the first geologic maps of large areas on which rocks containing similar fossils were shown.
他们出版了首批覆盖大片区域的地质图，图上标出了含有相似化石的岩石。
By careful observation of the rocks and their fossils, these men and other geologists were able to recognize rocks of the same age on opposite sides of the English Channel.
通过仔细观察岩石及其所含化石，这些人和其他地质学家得以辨认出英吉利海峡两岸同一年代的岩石。
William Smith was able to apply his knowledge of fossils in a very practical way.
威廉·史密斯得以把自己的化石知识运用到非常实际的用途上。
He was an engineer building canals in England, which has lots of vegetation and few surface exposures of rock.
他是在英格兰修建运河的工程师，而英格兰植被茂盛，地表很少有裸露的岩石。
He needed to know what rocks he could expect to find on the hills through which he had to build a canal.
他需要知道，在运河必须穿过的那些山丘上，自己预计会找到哪些岩石。
Often he could tell what kind of rock was likely to be below the surface by examining the fossils that had eroded from the rocks of the hillside or by digging a small hole to find fossils.
他查看从山坡岩石上侵蚀脱落的化石，或者挖个小洞找化石，往往就能判断出地表以下可能是哪种岩石。
Knowing what rocks to expect allowed Smith to estimate costs and determine what tools were needed for the job.
知道会遇到哪些岩石，史密斯就能估算成本，并确定这项工程需要哪些工具。
Smith and others knew that the succession of life forms preserved as fossils is useful for understanding how and when the rocks formed.
史密斯等人知道，保存为化石的各种生命形式，其演替顺序有助于了解这些岩石如何形成、何时形成。
Only later did scientists develop a theory to explain that succession.
直到后来，科学家们才提出了解释这种演替顺序的理论。